We're going to go on a dive to the deep sea.
[AI] 我们要去深海潜水。
and anyone that's had that lovely opportunity
[AI] 任何一个有机会的人
knows that for about two and half hours on the way down.
[AI] 在下山的路上，我知道了大约两个半小时。
it's a perfectly positively pitch-black world.
[AI] 这是一个完全漆黑的世界。
And we used to see the most mysterious animals out the window
[AI] 我们过去常常看到窗外最神秘的动物
that you couldn't describe:
[AI] 你无法描述的：
these blinking lights -- a world of bioluminescence. like fireflies.
[AI] 这些闪烁的灯光——一个生物发光的世界。像萤火虫一样。
Dr. Edith Widder -- she's now at the Ocean Research and Conservation Association --
[AI] 伊迪丝·维德博士——她现在在海洋研究和保护协会工作--
was able to come up with a camera that could capture some of these incredible animals.
[AI] 他发明了一台摄像机，可以捕捉到这些不可思议的动物。
and that's what you're seeing here on the screen.
[AI] 这就是你在屏幕上看到的。
That's all bioluminescence. Like I said: just like fireflies.
[AI] 这都是生物发光。就像我说的：就像萤火虫一样。
There's a flying turkey under a tree. (Laughter)
[AI] 树下有只会飞的火鸡。（众笑）
I'm a geologist by training. But I love that.
[AI] 我是一名受过训练的地质学家。但我喜欢这样。
And you see. some of the bioluminescence they use to avoid being eaten.
[AI] 你看。它们用来避免被吃掉的一些生物发光。
some they use to attract prey.
[AI] 有些是用来吸引猎物的。
but all of it. from an artistic point of view. is just positively amazing.
[AI] 但这一切。从艺术的角度来看。真是太神奇了。
And a lot of what goes on inside --
[AI] 里面发生了很多事情--
There's a fish with glowing eyes. pulsating eyes.
[AI] 有一条鱼眼睛发光。跳动的眼睛。
Some of the colors are designed to hypnotize.
[AI] 有些颜色是用来催眠的。
these lovely patterns.
[AI] 这些可爱的图案。
And then this last one.
[AI] 然后是最后一个。
one of my favorites. this pinwheel design.
[AI] 我的最爱之一。这是风车的设计。
Just absolutely amazing. every single dive.
[AI] 简直太神奇了。每一次潜水。
That's the unknown world. and today we've only explored
[AI] 那是未知的世界。今天我们只探索了
about 3 percent of what's out there in the ocean.
[AI] 大约3%的海洋生物。
Already we've found the world's highest mountains.
[AI] 我们已经发现了世界上最高的山脉。
the world's deepest valleys.
[AI] 世界上最深的山谷。
underwater lakes. underwater waterfalls --
[AI] 水下湖泊。水下瀑布--
a lot of that we shared with you from the stage.
[AI] 我们在舞台上与你分享了很多。
And in a place where we thought no life at all.
[AI] 在一个我们认为没有生命的地方。
we find more life. we think. and diversity and density
[AI] 我们发现了更多的生命。我们认为。以及多样性和密度
than the tropical rainforest.
[AI] 而不是热带雨林。
which tells us that we don't know much about this planet at all.
[AI] 这告诉我们，我们对这个星球的了解并不多。
There's still 97 percent.
[AI] 还有97%。
and either that 97 percent is empty or just full of surprises.
[AI] 这97%要么是空的，要么就是充满了惊喜。
But I want to jump up to shallow water now
[AI] 但我现在想跳到浅水区
and look at some creatures that are positively amazing.
[AI] 看看那些令人惊叹的生物。
Cephalopods -- head-foots. As a kid I knew them as calamari. mostly. (Laughter)
[AI] 头足类——头足类。小时候我就知道他们是卡拉马里人。主要地（众笑）
This is an octopus.
[AI] 这是一只章鱼。
This is the work of Dr. Roger Hanlon at the Marine Biological Lab.
[AI] 这是海洋生物实验室罗杰·汉隆博士的工作。
and it's just fascinating how cephalopods can.
[AI] 头足类动物的能力真是太神奇了。
with their incredible eyes. sense their surroundings.
[AI] 用他们难以置信的眼睛。感知他们周围的环境。
look at light. look at patterns.
[AI] 看看灯。看看模式。
Here's an octopus moving across the reef.
[AI] 这里有一只章鱼正在穿过礁石。
finds a spot to settle down. curls up and then disappears into the background.
[AI] 找个地方安顿下来。卷曲，然后消失在背景中。
Tough thing to do.
[AI] 很难做的事。
In the next bit. we're going to see a couple squid.
[AI] 在下一位。我们要去看几只乌贼。
Now males. when they fight.
[AI] 现在是男性。当他们打架的时候。
if they're really aggressive. they turn white.
[AI] 如果他们真的好斗。它们变白了。
And these two males are fighting.
[AI] 这两个男人在打架。
They do it by bouncing their butts together.
[AI] 他们通过把屁股弹跳在一起来实现。
which is an interesting concept.
[AI] 这是一个有趣的概念。
Now. here's a male on the left and a female on the right.
[AI] 现在左边是一只雄性，右边是一只雌性。
and the male has managed to split his coloration
[AI] 而这只雄性已经成功地分裂了他的肤色
so the female only always sees the kinder. gentler squid in him. (Laughter)
[AI] 所以女性总是看到更善良的人。他是个温柔的乌贼。（众笑）
Let's take a look at it again. Watch the coloration:
[AI] 让我们再看一看。观看色彩：
white on the right. brown on the left.
[AI] 右边是白色。左边是布朗。
He takes a step back. he's keeping off the other males by splitting his body.
[AI] 他后退了一步。他把自己的身体劈开以避开其他雄性。
and comes up on the other side --
[AI] 从另一边上来--
Bingo!
[AI] 答对 了
Now. I'm told that's not not just a squid phenomenon with males. but I don't know.
[AI] 现在我听说这不仅仅是雄性乌贼的现象。但我不知道。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Cuttlefish. I love cuttlefish.
[AI] 乌贼我喜欢墨鱼。
This is a Giant Australian Cuttlefish.
[AI] 这是一只巨大的澳大利亚乌贼。
And there he is. his droopy little eyes up here.
[AI] 他就在那里。他那下垂的小眼睛。
But they can do pretty amazing things. too.
[AI] 但是他们可以做很多令人惊奇的事情。也
Here we're going to see one backing into a crevice.
[AI] 在这里，我们将看到一个倒退到裂缝中。
and watch his tentacles --
[AI] 看着他的触手--
he just pulls them in. makes them look just like algae.
[AI] 他只是把他们拉进来。使它们看起来像藻类。
Disappears right into the background.
[AI] 消失在背景中。
Positively amazing. Here's two males fighting.
[AI] 真是太棒了。这里有两个男人在打架。
Once again. they're smart enough. these cephalopods;
[AI] 再一次他们足够聪明。这些头足类；
they know not to hurt each other.
[AI] 他们知道不要互相伤害。
But look at the patterns that they can do with their skin.
[AI] 但是看看他们的皮肤可以做什么。
That's an amazing thing.
[AI] 这是一件了不起的事情。
Here's an octopus.
[AI] 这是一只章鱼。
Sometimes they don't want to be seen when they move.
[AI] 有时他们不想在移动时被人看见。
because predators can see them.
[AI] 因为捕食者可以看到它们。
This guy can make himself look like a rock.
[AI] 这家伙可以让自己看起来像块石头。
and. looking at his environment.
[AI] 和看看他的环境。
can actually slide across the bottom.
[AI] 实际上可以在底部滑动。
using the waves and the shadows so he can't be seen.
[AI] 利用波浪和阴影让他看不见。
His motion blends right into the background --
[AI] 他的动作与背景融为一体--
the moving rock trick.
[AI] 移动的岩石技巧。
So. we're learning lots new from the shallow water.
[AI] 所以我们从浅水区学到了很多新东西。
Still exploring the deep. but learning lots from the shallow water.
[AI] 仍在探索深海。但是从浅水中学习了很多。
There's a good reason why:
[AI] 这有一个很好的理由：
the shallow water's full of predators -- here's a barracuda --
[AI] 浅水区到处都是捕食者这是梭鱼--
and if you're an octopus or a cephalopod.
[AI] 如果你是章鱼或头足类动物。
you need to really understand how to use your surroundings to hide.
[AI] 你需要真正了解如何利用周围环境来隐藏自己。
In the next scene. you're going to see a nice coral bottom.
[AI] 在下一个场景中。你会看到一个漂亮的珊瑚底。
And you see that an octopus would stand out
[AI] 你看，章鱼会脱颖而出
very easily there if you couldn't use your camouflage.
[AI] 如果你不能用你的伪装，在那里很容易。
use your skin to change color and texture.
[AI] 使用你的皮肤来改变颜色和纹理。
Here's some algae in the foreground --
[AI] 前景中有一些藻类--
and an octopus.
[AI] 还有一只章鱼。
Ain't that amazing?
[AI] 这不是很神奇吗？
Now. Roger spooked him. so he took off in a cloud of ink.
[AI] 现在罗杰吓了他一跳。于是他在一团墨水中离开了。
and when he lands. the octopus says. "Oh. I've been seen.
[AI] 当他着陆时。章鱼说。“哦，有人看见我了。
The best thing to do is to get as big as I can get."
[AI] 最好的办法就是尽我所能地变大。"
That big brown makes his eyespot very big.
[AI] 那个大棕色使他的眼点很大。
So. he's bluffing. Let's do it backwards.
[AI] 所以他在虚张声势。让我们倒着做吧。
I thought he was joking when he first showed it to me.
[AI] 他第一次给我看的时候我还以为他在开玩笑呢。
I thought it was all graphics. So here it is in reverse.
[AI] 我以为都是图形。所以这里是相反的。
Watch the skin color; watch the skin texture.
[AI] 注意肤色；观察皮肤纹理。
Just an amazing animal. it can change color and texture
[AI] 只是一只神奇的动物。它可以改变颜色和纹理
to match the surroundings.
[AI] 与周围环境相匹配。
Watch him blend right into this algae.
[AI] 看着他融入这海藻。
One. two. three.
[AI] 一二三
And now he's gone. and so am I. Thank you very much. (Applause)
[AI] 现在他走了。我也是。非常感谢。（掌声）